<content type="application/x.deki-text" title="Plug-Ins" unsafe="true"><body xmlns:eval="http://mindtouch.com/2007/dekiscript"><p class="comment">The following script renders the table of contents for this page.</p>
<pre class="script">template(&quot;MindTouch/IDF/Views/TableOfContents&quot;);</pre>
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p class="comment">Use the section below to provide a short description of the tutorial. The section is also used by other pages to provide an abstract of this page. The lead sentence should tell the reader enough about the tutorial to help them decide whether to read on or not.</p>
<p>With your Sugar Ultimate subscription, you have access to the Microsoft Office and Lotus Notes plug-ins. You can download and install your plug-ins as described in <a title="04_Find_Answers/02KB/01Getting_Started/How_to_Download_and_Install_Sugar_Plug-Ins" href.path="//04_Find_Answers/02KB/01Getting_Started/Downloading_and_Installing_Sugar_Plug-ins">this article</a>. We recommend to always run the latest release of the plug-ins as they are backwards compatible and we only support the latest releases. Read below to understand what the primary functions are of each plug-in so that you can quickly decide what will help you best in integrating with Sugar.</p>
<h3>Microsoft Outlook</h3>
<p>The Outlook plug-in allows you to perform a number of tasks. First and foremost, you can archive emails from Outlook to the desired record(s) in Sugar such as contacts, accounts, opportunities, etc. Additional functions include contact, meeting, and task synchronization, lead, contact, account and case creation, and more! Review the <a title="02_Documentation/03_Sugar_Plug-ins/Sugar_Plug-ins_6.4/Sugar_Plug-in_for_MS_Outlook_6.4.0_User_Guide" href.path="//02_Documentation/03_Sugar_Plug-ins/Sugar_Plug-ins_6.5/Sugar_Plug-in_for_MS_Outlook_User_Guide_6.4.0">user guide for the Outlook plug-in</a> so that you can quickly realize the full potential of this integration!</p>
<h3>Microsoft Word</h3>
<p>The Word plug-in allows you to perform mail merges either from Word or from Sugar. Please note that in order to use this plug-in, the 'Enable mail merge' option must be selected under Admin &gt; System Settings as well as the 'Mail Merge' option under the Advanced tab of the user's profile. The <a title="02_Documentation/03_Sugar_Plug-ins/Sugar_Plug-ins_6.4/Sugar_Plug-in_for_MS_Word_6.4.0_User_Guide" href.path="//02_Documentation/03_Plug-ins/Sugar_Plug-ins_6.4/Sugar_Plug-in_for_MS_Word_6.4.0_User_Guide">Word plug-in user guide</a> provides you the next steps to generate your mail merge document.</p>
<h3>Microsoft Excel</h3>
<p>When using Sugar, you may find that you want to update data that isn't normally available through the Mass Update interface. You may also want to pull raw data from your Sugar instance to integrate with other reports and the Excel plug-in provides you with the necessary tools to perform these robust actions. With our Excel plug-in user guide, you will learn to harness the power of this tool to fully analyze and update your data.</p>
<h3>Lotus Notes</h3>
<p>With the Lotus Notes plug-in, you will be able to link documents, sync records (contacts, meetings, etc.), create new records and much more! Our <a title="02_Documentation/03_Sugar_Plug-ins/Sugar_Plug-ins_6.4/Sugar_Plug-in_for_MS_Excel_User_Guide_6.2" href.path="//02_Documentation/03_Plug-ins/Sugar_Plug-ins_6.4/Sugar_Plug-in_for_MS_Excel_User_Guide_6.2">Notes plug-in user guide</a> will take you through the steps of activating the plug-in and utilizing all the features.</p>
<h2>Related</h2>
<p class="comment">This section automatically lists related pages, such as child pages or pages related by tags.&#160; Remove this section if you do not want to show related pages.</p>
<pre class="script">template(&quot;MindTouch/IDF/SeeAlso&quot;)</pre><br /></body></content>