<content type="application/x.deki-text" title="Administrators" unsafe="true"><body xmlns:eval="http://mindtouch.com/2007/dekiscript"><div class="landign-page" id="get-started"> <p class="landing-intro">Getting started with Sugar is a simple, straightforward process. Select the section below that we can assist you in setting up and configuring.</p> <div class="enclosed-block rounded-corners shadow" id="on-demand"> <h2 class="landing-subtitle"><a title="Free Trial" href.path="//01_Get_Started/02_Administrators/01_Free_Trial">Free Trial</a></h2> Are you interested in trying Sugar to see what we have to offer? Our free trial gives you a snapshot experience of using Sugar from the perspective of a number of different roles in your business.&#160;</div> <div class="enclosed-block rounded-corners shadow" id="on-demand"> <h2 class="landing-subtitle"><a title="Community Edition" href.path="//01_Get_Started/02_Administrators/02_Community_Edition">Community Edition</a></h2> <p>Community Edition offers a great opportunity to experience a large portion of the features and functionality we have in our paid versions. We can help you get set up from installation to configuration!</p> </div> <div class="enclosed-block rounded-corners shadow" id="on-demand"> <h2 class="landing-subtitle"><a title="Professional" href.path="//01_Get_Started/02_Administrators/03_Professional">Professional</a></h2> <p>Sugar Professional gives you all the critical features and functionality for businesses to be successful in maturing their customer relationships.&#160;</p> </div> <div class="enclosed-block rounded-corners shadow" id="on-site"> <h2 class="landing-subtitle"><a title="Corporate" href.path="//01_Get_Started/02_Administrators/04_Corporate">Corporate</a></h2> <p>Sugar Corporate gives you all the functionality of Professional with the added bonus of Mobile+ and increased support levels.&#160;</p> </div> <div class="enclosed-block rounded-corners shadow" id="mobile"> <h2 class="landing-subtitle"><a title="Enterprise" href.path="//01_Get_Started/02_Administrators/05_Enterprise">Enterprise</a></h2> <p>Whether you are looking run Sugar on your DB2 or Oracle database or you need a portal for your customers to interact with your business, Sugar Enterprise will drive you to a robust solution that is easy to maintain.</p> </div> <div class="enclosed-block rounded-corners shadow" id="plug-ins"> <h2 class="landing-subtitle"><a title="Ultimate" href.path="//01_Get_Started/02_Administrators/06_Ultimate">Ultimate</a></h2> <p>Sugar Ultimate provides you with access to all the best that we have to offer. Ultimate ensures you will have all the latest and greatest functionality and the support resources dedicated to your success.</p> </div>
</div></body></content>